

## Muziwandile Nkomo

Date of birth: 18/07/1998

Nationality: Zimbabwean

Gender: Male

## **CONTACT**

 4308 Bhejani rd Gwabalanda, 00000 Bulawayo, Zimbabwe (Home)

muziwandilenko@gmail.com

(+263) 789844536

https://muziwandileportfolio.netlify.app/

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ muzi-nkomo-2715701b9/

#### **ABOUT ME**

An experienced Dev Ops Engineer adept at guiding design teams, testing existing software, deploying changes to enhance the IT infrastructure, and assessing and establishing security protocols. I'll find ways to automate manual processes and save the company time and money

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

13/05/2019 - 17/10/2020 - Bulawayo, Zimbabwe

## Software developer

WozaTel

- Built modern applications using MySQL, Java, SQL server, and Spring and supported the company's development and testing processes
- Developed effective microservices and web services and created a series of unit tests to ensure that the projects passed all quality benchmarks
- Worked with a team of expert coders to write maintainable code and maintain existing software to improve performance and fix bugs
- Consulted with clients to identify their projects' specifications and follow up with deployed applications' status and any technical issues
- Developed expertise in CRM and gained trust in clients

#### 15/12/2020 - 28/07/2021 - Pretoria, South Africa

## **Devops engineer**

BushCyber

- Identified manual processes that could be automated to enhance speed or save money; considered the entire company IT infrastructure when designing improvements
- Monitored and regularly updated essential sections of code; designed, built, and tested proposed changes to existing software
- Oversaw and managed the development, computer coding, testing, and deployment operations of multiple teams
- Assisted with the setup of a cloud-based system and the successful migration of all relevant data
- Prepared systems testing reports for review by upper-level management

### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

14/09/2018 - 14/07/2022 - Bulawayo, Zimbabwe

### BSc Computer Science

National University of Science and Technology

Address P.O. BOX AC 939, Ascot, Bulawayo, Zimbabwe | Website <a href="https://www.nust.ac.zw/">https://www.nust.ac.zw/</a> | Field of study Information and Communication Technologies | Final grade 2.2 | Level in EQF EQF level 8 | Thesis Traffic Sign Detection using AI

#### LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Ndebele

**OTHER LANGUAGE(S):** 

**English** 

<b>Listening</b> C2	<b>Reading</b> C2	Spoken production C2	<b>Spoken</b> <b>interaction</b> C2	<b>Writing</b> C2
French				
<b>Listening</b> A2	<b>Reading</b> A2	Spoken production A2	Spoken interaction A2	<b>Writing</b> A2

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

## **My Digital Skills**

NoSQL Database MongoDB DynamoDB / Spring (Core, MVC, Spring Data, Batch, Security) / C++ / Linux / Ruby Scripting / Bash-Script / Make, ANT, Maven, Jenkins, RPM / Java Servlets Apache Maven Apache Tomcat JDBC Hibernate ORM Linux

## **Programming Languages**

Java Oracle / Terraforms / Javascript / Python

#### **Backend**

Basic - Groovy / Apache, Nginx , Tomcat, Node.js / Tensorflow, Keras, OpenCV, Git, AWS, Selenium, Docker, Kubernetes / Continuous Integration (CI) and deployment (CD) (Jenkins Github Actions GitLab / Containerisation: Docker, Dock

## **PROJECTS**

13/06/2020 - 17/09/2020

## **Traffic Sign Detection using AI**

https://github.com/Muzi12345632/TSR-Deploy

Real time detection of traffic signs using Neural Networks and computer vision. Able to classify 43 different classes of traffic signs from GTSDB in real time

14/08/2020 - 07/01/2021

#### **Reinforcement Learning Ai**

#### https://github.com/Muzi12345632/Reinforcement Learning Al

Reinforcement learning is an area of machine learning concerned with how intelligent agents ought to take actions in an environment in order to maximize the notion of cumulative reward. The purpose of reinforcement learning is for the agent to learn an optimal, or nearly-optimal, policy that maximizes the "reward function" or other user-provided reinforcement signal that accumulates from the immediate rewards. Reinforcement Learning also finds application in self-driving cars to train an agent for optimizing trajectories and dynamically planning the most efficient path.



# NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY ACADEMIC TRANSCRIPT

P. O. BOX AC 939 ASCOT, BULAWAYO ZIMBABWE TELEPHONE: +263 9 285917

+263 9 282842

FAX: +263 9 286803

Student Name:

Umuziwandile Nkomo

Date of Birth:

18 July, 1998

Place of Birth:

Nkulumane Clinic, Bulawayo, Zimbabwe

Student No:

N0182791P

Department:

**Computer Science** 

Programme Title:

Bachelor of Science Honours Degree in Computer Science

Start Date:

ARETAGADUM

August, 2018

Language of Instruction:

NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF

SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

5 0 SEP 2022

DEPUTY REGISTRAR-ACADEMIC

English

Degree Class Awarded:

Lower Second Division (2.2)

#### PART I RESULTS (2018-2019 Academic Year)

Course Code	<u>Course Title</u>	Overall Mark %	Classification
SCS1101	Introduction to Computer Science and Programming	55.00	ASSEMBLE PARTY PARTY AND ADDRESS OF THE PARTY
SCS1102	Mathematical Foundation of Computer Science	42.00	ACADIM TRANS FORMS IN ACADIM
SCS1103	Operating Systems Concepts	58.00	P
SCS1105	Computational Research Methods	68.00	2.1
SMA1101	Calculus	30.00	F
SMA1102	Linear Algebra	50.00	Р
CTL1101	Conflict Transformation and Leadership	64 00	2.2
SCS1202	Database Concepts	55.00	2
SCS1204	Logic Design and Switching Circuits	65.00	2.1
SCS1205	Software Engineering Concepts	35.00	ACADI METALANI
SCS1206	Visual Programming Concepts and Development	54.00	Р
SCS1207	Structured Program Design and Programming	57.00	AUCHICTE AND PROMISE

#### PART I CARRY RESULTS (2019-2020 Academic Year)

Course Code	Course Title	Overall Mark %	Classification
SCS1102	Mathematical Foundation of Computer Science	59.00	p
SMA1101	Calculus	36.00	F

DEPUTY REGISTRAR (ACADEMIC





# NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY ACADEMIC TRANSCRIPT

P. O. BOX AC 939 ASCOT, BULAWAYO ZIMBABWE TELEPHONE: +263 9 285917

+263 9 282842

FAX: +263 9 286803

SCS1205

Software Engineering Concepts

63.00

2.2

PART I CARRY RESULTS (2020-2	2021 Academic Year)
------------------------------	---------------------

Course Code	Course Title	I NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF	Overall Mark %	Classification
SMA1101	Calculus	SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY	58.00	P
ALADAM TAMBATA	Part I Overall	3 0 SEP 2022	59.00	P
		THE RESERVE AND ADDRESS OF THE PROPERTY OF THE		

PART II RESULTS (2019-2020 Academic Year)

DEPUTY REGISTRAR-ACADEMIC

Course Code	Course Title	Overall Mark %	Classification
SCS2101	Computer Data Communications	63.00	2.2
SCS2102	Computer Architecture	52.00	P
SCS2103	Data Structures and Algorithms	68.00	2.1
SCS2104	Structured Systems Analysis and Design	54.00	Р
SCS2108	Object Oriented Software Concepts and Development	54.00	P
SORS2104	Operations Research Techniques	50.00	Р
SCS2201 .	Software Design Methodology	57.00	Р
SCS2203	Advanced Mathematical Structures for Computing	55.00	P
SCS2204	Internet and Web Designing	67.00	2.1
SCS2206	Computing in Society	73.00	2.1
SCS2207	Computer Networks and Applications	59.00	Р
SCS2209	Computational Modelling	58.00	P
ALL ALL AND LANGUAGE TO THE ALL ALL AND	Part il Overall	59.00	Р

#### PART III RESULTS (2020-2021 Academic Year)

Course Code	Course Title	THE TANKS OF THE REPORT OF THE THE THE THE TANKS OF THE T	Overall Mark %	Classification
SCS3200	Industrial Attachment	RECORD FOR THE STANDARD STANDARD SERVICE AND THE STANDARD SERVICE SERVICES AND THE STANDARD SERVICES AND THE SERVICES AND THE STANDARD SERVICES AND THE SERVICES AND THE STANDARD SERVICES AND THE SERVICES A	68.00	2.1
	Part III Overall	STRANGGRAFTIN (KT. ACADEM) THE ANAGEMENT NUMBER OF ACADEM THE ANAGEMENT NUMBER OF ACADEM THE THE ANAGEMENT NUMBER OF ACADEM THE THE ACADEM THE THE ACADEM THE THE ACADEM THE THE ACADEM THE	68.00	2.1

PART IV RESULTS (2021-2022 Academic Year)

DEPUTY REGISTRAR (ACADEMIC)

Nedelse

N0182791P



Page 2 of 3



# NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY ACADEMIC TRANSCRIPT

P. O. BOX AC 939 ASCOT, BULAWAYO ZIMBABWE TELEPHONE: +263 9 285917

+263 9 282842

FAX: +263 9 286803

Course Code	Course Title	Overall Mark %	Classification
SCS4101	Artificial Intelligence	69.00	2.1
SCS4103	Software Project Management	51.00	Р
SCS4108	Simulation and Modelling	67.00	2.1
SCS4110 (4)	Information Systems Security and Auditing	62.00	2.2
SCS4111	Enterprise Architecture Programming	57.00	Р
SCI4201	Digital Forensics	66.00	2.1
SCS4000	Final Year Project	59.00	Р
SCS4201	Databases Design and Management	57.00	Р
SCS4203	Computer Graphics	60.00	2.2
SCS4207	Expert and Decision Support Systems	57.00	Р
SCS4208	Distributed Computing	64.00	2.2
CADENC HAND BY THE TAIL OF THE CADENCY THAN THE TAIL OF THE CADENCY THAN THE CADENCY THE CADENCY THAN THE CADENCY THAN THE CADENCY THAN THE CADENCY THE CADENCY THE CADENCY THAN THE CADENCY THE C	Part IV Overall	61.00	2.2
PRIZES AWARDED:	NONE		

He/She has completed the requirements for the award of the BACHELOR OF SCIENCE HONOURS DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE.

NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

S 0 SEP 2022

DEPUTY REGISTRAR-ACADEMIC

DEPUTY REGISTRAR (ACADEMIC)

Gradelse

DATE:

30 September, 2022

Page 3 of 3

N0182791P



## NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

Waste Land Waste Land Waste Land	Santa days, and a visual	IVIA	RKING SCHEME ANI		ES .		
A SON WAS STANDED	And the second second	The Court of	(Applicable as from		1		
A TRUST CONTRACTOR OF THE PARTY	Bachelor				duate Degrees And Dipl	A Part of the Control	
% (Percentage)	Degree Classifi	ication	<u>Division</u>	% (Percentage)	Degree Classification	Division	
75+	1	orange and the	First Division	70 and above	D	Distinction	
65-74	2.1	Life Stand M	Upper Second Division	60 - 69	M	Merit	
55-64	2.2	SERVICE SERVICE	Lower Second Division	50 – 59	P	. Pass	
45-54	P	CHECKER IN COLUMN TO THE COLUMN TWO IN COLUMN TO THE COLUMN THE COLUMN TO THE COLUMN T	Pass				
The state of the s	STATE OF THE STATE	dia managan da Managan da Managan da Ma	The state of the s		200 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 100	S WATER BY STAND	
Below 45	Fail Supplement	ahla	ACK AT SOLEHOE STAND WINDS DATE OF THE STANDARD	Below 50	Fail		
35-44 0-34	Not Supple		THE STATE OF THE S	40 – 49 0-39	Supplementable		
0-34	Not Supple	пепале	Farmon Forest and payment and particles and particles of the forest and particles of the farmon and particles of t	0-39	Not Supplementable	And the second	
VISONALINA SERVEL IN ACRE	Charles To The Control of the Contro	- 15 TO TO THE TOTAL PROPERTY OF THE TOTAL P	om 2015 for General Ma	The state of the s	The first of the second	AND A CONTRACTOR	
Grade-Point Avera  Degree Class	age (GPA) & ification	<u>%</u>	(Percentage)	Degree Classifica	tion <u>Divis</u>	<u>ion</u>	
3.81 - 4.00 Di	stinction		80-100	D	Distino	ction	
3.31 - 3.80 Merit		70-79	M	Mer	Merit		
2.91 - 3.30 Credit		60-69	C	Cred	lit		
2.50 - 2.90 Pass		50-59	P	Pas	S		
0.00 - 2.49	9 Fail		0-49	rational viscosi <b>F</b>	Fai	Fail	
A 12 March 1	(Applic	able as	from 2016 and to Maste	ers Degrees and D	iplomas only)	TA SHALL IN STREET	
<u>% (Per</u>	centage)	MATERIAL TO	Degree Classifica	ntion	Division		
80 an	d above	464,5876 87,385 464,5876 87,345 649,5876 87,345	D	MATERIAL DATE OF ANDREAST WATER	Distinction		
7(	)-79	SURDRIVERT IN	M		Merit		
	)-69	dial SN + LDM	C	AND THE PROPERTY OF THE PROPER	Credit		
	)-59	STATE OF THE STATE	Parameter and the same of the		Pass		
Bel	ow 50	diadente au illi diadente au discontre	, which is the second discount of the second secon	ANTORONIC MUSICAL AND	Fail		
Value of the state	(A	Applical	ble as from 2016 and to		The state of the s	THE THE THE STREET	
<u>% (Per</u>	centage)	AND THE WAY THE	Degree Classifica	ntion	<b>Division</b>	CONTROL OF TAXABLE	
7	<b>'</b> 5-	ON DEMONSTRATION	ALA CUATTORIAN MAGANATURAN	WHEN THE PROPERTY OF THE PROPE	First Division		
6.5	5-74	Machine Com	2.1	A SET THE WAY OF THE WAY OF THE PARTY OF THE	Upper Second Division		
	)-64	CHICAN BLOW	2.2	WATER TO SERVICE THE SERVICE T	Lower Second Div	ision	
	)-59	Shushi di M	P	Mary Mary Mary Market Special Strategy	Pass		
Bel	ow 50	APOST ST. IN	F	AN DAY AND A PART OF ANY OWN THE PART OF T	Fail		

This transcript is valid only if it is signed and bears the National University of Science and Technology Stamp

